<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="MD_CC_PRO_045_1676_Lilly" xml:lang="en">Elizabeth Lilly. Will.</title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <author></author>
                <editor>Emily Boyer</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>"Maryland, Register of Wills Records, 1629-1999." 
                    Images. FamilySearch. <ref target="http://FamilySearch.org">http://FamilySearch.org</ref>: 3 December 2024. 
                    Citing Prerogative Court. Hall of Records, Annapolis.</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)">Elizabeth Lilly. Will.</head>
                <p>In the name of God Amen. The 15th day of November 1676. in
                    <lb/>the 28th of the Reigne &amp;c I <persName type="author">Elizabeth Lilly</persName> of <placeName>Charles County in the pronvince of
                    <lb/>maryland</placeName> sick of body but of sound and perfect memory praise be given to god
                    <lb/>for the <unclear reason="illegible">fame</unclear> and knowing the uncertainty of this life on earth and being 
                    <lb/>desirous to settle things in order do make this my last will and testament
                    <lb/>in manner and form following <unclear reason="illegible">viz.</unclear> First and princpally I commend my soule
                    <lb/>to God Almighty my Creator and <unclear reason="illegible">afoundly</unclear> believing that I shall receive full
                    <lb/>pardon and <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> of my sins and be saved by the merits and <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                <lb/>Death of my beloved Savior and redeemer Jesus Christ and my body to the
                    <lb/>earth from where it were taken to be buried in decent Christian manner
                    <lb/>and as touching such worldly good, as the Lord in <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> merry hath sent me my will
                    <lb/>and meaning is that it be bestowed as hereafter by this my will is <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                <lb/>First I doe revoke and make said all former wills by me made &amp; declare &amp;
                    <lb/>appoint this my last will and testament
                </p>
                <p>List
                    <lb/>Item I will that all those Debts that I have of right or <unclear reason="illegible">conceince</unclear> to any manner of person
                    <lb/>shall be well and truly paid in convenient time after my decease by my Executor
                    <lb/>beneath named.
                </p>
                <p>Item I give and bequeath to my lo. father in law <persName type="father-in-law" xml:id="PeterCarr">Peter <surname>Carr</surname></persName> all &amp; all manner of Estate
                    <lb/>virg. Lands chattles moveables &amp; Immoveables whatsoever to him and his heirs forever 
                </p>
                <p>Item I nominate and appoint my aforesaid father in law Peter Carr my whole and 
                    <lb/>Sole executor In testimony whereof I have hereunto set my hand and seal
                    <lb/>the day and year above.
                </p>
                <p>Signed Sealed &amp; Deliv. as my last will
                    <lb/>&amp; Testimony in the presents of us
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">Anthony <surname>Bridges</surname></persName>.- <persName type="witness">Joseph <unclear reason="illegible">B</unclear></persName>
                    <lb/>sign
                    <lb/>Elizabeth Lilly
                </p>
                <pb/>
                <p>On the back of the aforegoing was enforsed the following probit (to will)
                    <lb/><date>December 30th 1676</date> By virtue of a commision from the Judge for Probate of
                    <lb/>C. Mills &amp;c. dated the 30th day of November 1676 to me <unclear reason="illegible">discreeted</unclear> and I called before me
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">Joseph <unclear reason="illegible">Bullettt</unclear></persName> one of the witnesses to the within written will who on the day above
                    <lb/>written by his oath proved the within written will <persName>Anthony <unclear reason="illegible">Bredges</unclear></persName> the other witness
                    <lb/>in Virginia I could not call before me
                    <lb/>4 sides
                    <lb/><persName>Benjamin <surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>