<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="xx" xml:lang="en"><!-- Title ex. John Smith. Will --></title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <author></author>
                <editor></editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Signed Sealed Delivered</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)"><!-- John Smith. Will --></head>
                <p>In the name of God amen. In the year of our Lord God 1670 March 20th 
                    <lb/>I Nicholas Emanson of Charles County in the province of Maryland being sick and 
                    <lb/>weak in body but of good and perfect memory thank be to god do make this my 
                    <lb/>last will and testament in manner and form following that is to say 
                    <lb/>first I bequeath my soul and [unclear] into the hand of the almighty God my heavenly father
                    <lb/>by [u?] home of his [unclear] and only grace I trust to be saved and [n?] unto eternal 
                    <lb/>[trust?] though the Death of my savior and redeemer Jesus Chrust in whose [precious?]
                    <lb/>blood I sell the whole and only hope of my salvation my [weathered?] body in hope 
                    <lb/>of a joyful resurrection I commit to the earth to be with such charge
                    <lb/>and in such place as my Executor hereafter named shall think [till?] and 
                    <lb/>[touching?] the distribution of my mortall goods I disperse of the same a followith
                </p>
                <p>
                 <lb/><list>
                     <item>First I will that all such Debts as I owe shall be truly paid. 
                     </item>
                     
                     <item>Secondly I give unto my Daughter [unclear] one thousand two hundred pounds of 
                         Tobacco to be [paid?] to her or her heirs by my Executor hereafter named.
                     </item>
                     
                     <item>All of the rest of my Estate reall and pesonal lands goods cattles and chattels 
                         Whatsoever I give and bequeath unto my loving wife Elizabeth and my 
                         Daughter Mary Emanson to be equally divided between them and my Daughter
                         Marys share to be delivered unto her when she comes to be [sixteen?] years of age 
                     </item>
                     
                     <item>I will and ordaine that the part and portion of my Daughter Mary remain in 
                         The hands of my wife Elizabeth Emanson during the time of her minority 
                         And that my Executor out of the profits to be got by the use of the said 
                         Marys part or portion become die to her and if she dye before the said part or portion 
                         Become due to her then the said part portion and legacy of her [unclear] dying 
                         Shall be all the disposal of my Executor.
                     </item>
                 </list> 
                </p>
                <p>Lastly I make and ordaine the said Elizabeth Emanson my wife to be full 
                    Hole and sole Executor of this my last will and testament by me in any [waife?] heretofore made 
                    Or declared I [witness?] whereof I have hereunto set my hand and seal the day
                    
                    
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>