<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="MD_CC_PRO_059_1677_Ashbrooke" xml:lang="en">John Ashbrooke Will.</title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <author></author>
                <editor>Emily Boyer</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Signed Sealed and Delivered</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)">John Ashbrooke Will.</head>
                <p>In the name of God Amen. The last will and testament of <persName type="witness">John
                    <lb/><surname>Ashbrooke</surname></persName> in <placeName>Charles County</placeName> being in perfect memory.
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> I give and bequeath my soule unto the Almighty God and my body to
                    <lb/>be entered in the ground and in it to be desently buried as my dear wife
                    <lb/>shall see to it.
                </p>
                <p>2d I give and bequeath unto my loving <persName type="spouse" xml:id="MrsAshbrooke">wife</persName> <measure commodity="livestock" quantity="1" xml:id="MrsAshbrooke">one chow call by the name of
                    <lb/><name>Juyne</name></measure> with a <measure type="livestock" quantity="1" xml:id="MrsAshbrooke">chow calf</measure> by her side now naming. I give unto my sonne <persName type="son" xml:id="JamesAshbrooke">James</persName>
                <lb/><measure commodity="livestock" quantity="1" xml:id="JamesAshbrooke">one chow called by the name of <name>fortune</name></measure> and <measure commodity="livestock" quantity="2" xml:id="JohnAshbrooke">two yearlings being heiffers</measure>
                    <lb/>and come of the above said chow Juyne and all the land that at this 
                    <lb/>present belongs and dappertains unto me  the sd. John onely my wife to enjoy
                    <lb/>the sd. land for her life time provided she keeps herself unmaryed but
                    <lb/>is that she should mary that the the said James shall tke the said land
                    <lb/>into his possession and that my wife shall have nothing to do with it.
                </p>
                <p>3d I give and bequeath unto my Daughter <persName type="daughter" xml:id="Keese"><unclear reason="illegible">Keese</unclear></persName> <measure commodity="livestock" quantity="1" xml:id="Keese">one yoing heafer at two years
                <lb/>of age Called by the name of <name>Gentle</name></measure>.
                </p>
                <p>4 I give and bequeath unto my Daughter <persName xml:id="Elizabeth">Elizabeth</persName> <measure commodity="livestock" quantity="1" xml:id="Elizabeth">one three year olf heaffer
                <lb/>Called by the name of <unclear reason="illegible">Ham</unclear></measure>.
                </p>
                <p>5. I give and bequeath unto my Daughter <persName type="daughter" xml:id="AnnAshbrooke">Ann</persName> <measure commodity="livestock" quantity="1" xml:id="AnnAshbrooke">one heaffer called by the name of
                    <lb/><name><unclear reason="illegible">Carmakin meat</unclear></name></measure> I desire that my sone <persName type="son" xml:id="JamesAshbrooke">James</persName> if I die shall be a free man and to
                    <lb/>disperse of himself as hee shall see fit and likewise to have <measure commodity="weapon" quantity="2" xml:id="JamesAshbrooke">two gunns</measure> which are at
                    <lb/>presentmy own but if I die to be at his <unclear reason="illegible">dispersing</unclear> meet for the house hold
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> my desire is that it shall remaine in the house for that good of them all
                    <lb/>and no <unclear reason="illegible">separation</unclear> to be made as <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> wainscoat I kept and a small <unclear reason="illegible">loc</unclear> that my
                    <lb/><catchwords>wife</catchwords>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>wife put her <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> in I give unto her.
                </p>
                <p>Sixthly I constitute and appoint my loving wife to be to be Executor and to see
                    <lb/>my will performed in all respects whatsoever as is above specified and to the
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible">confination</unclear> of which I have hereunto set my hand and seal the <date>seventeenth
                        <lb/>day of January in the year of our lord. 1677/8</date>.
                </p>
                <p>Signed Sealed &amp; Delivered
                    <lb/>In the presents of us
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">Hrt. <surname>Burghitt</surname></persName> - <persName type="witness">Simon <surname>Stephens</surname></persName>
                    <lb/>John Ashbrooke
                </p>
                <p>On the back of the aforegoing will was Endorsed the following probate &amp; petition (to will)
                    <lb/><date>January 24th day 1678</date>. Then Simon Stephens being sworn upon the <unclear reason="illegible">Evangatent</unclear>
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> that he saw and heard John Ashbrooke deceased Sign Seal Deliver &amp;
                    <lb/>publish the within mentioned his Last will and testament.
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">John Stone</persName>
                </p>
                <p><placeName>Maryland</placeName> Jst. The Honorable <persName type="witness">Philip <surname>Colvert</surname></persName> Esquire Chancellor and Chief Judge
                    <lb/>on Comisary <unclear reason="illegible">Gen.</unclear> for probate of wlls and granting of administrations for the 
                    <lb/><placeName>province of Maryland</placeName> the Humble Petition of <persName>emprance Ashbrooke</persName>T &amp; <persName>Richard
                    <lb/>Clowder</persName> who sense the decease of the within named John Ashbrooke <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                    <lb/>with the said Temprance humbly showeth unto your hon. as.
                </p>
                <p>That your poor and humble petition Temprance Ashbrooke alias Clowder as
                    <lb/>also the above mentioned Richard Clowder who hath since s.d John Ashbrooke
                    <lb/>death Intermarried with the sd Temperance humbly <unclear reason="illegible">beegs</unclear> our hon. that they
                    <lb/>may have the liberty to renounce the within mentioned will that the sd
                    <lb/>Temprance in the life time of the said John Ashbrooke late of <placeName>Charles County</placeName>
                    <lb/>deceased proving him a true and faithfull wife unto him the said John in his
                    <lb/>life time and all - what follows unintelligable time of there lives together hath
                    <lb/>not him by any of the neighbourhood and uputed to have been any ways
                    <lb/>- what follows unintelligable Husband and was always willing and ayding
                    <lb/>and assisting her dear husband un his life time to worke and <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> and
                    <lb/>any lawfull indeavor for the <unclear reason="illegible">seaveing</unclear> the small <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> God in his mercy was
                    <lb/>pleased to find us during his maternal life yet <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> al the deacease of my 
                    <lb/><catchwords>dear</catchwords>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>Dear and Loving husnand <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> Ashbrooke he sd John made the within
                    <lb/>mentioned deedeas his last will and testament and in the said will
                    <lb/>hath not <unclear reason="illegible">gwen</unclear> me what in right and according to my life &amp; c
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible">conwensation</unclear> and obediance I had <unclear reason="illegible">indeaeour</unclear> towards him during his
                    <lb/>natural life in right he ought to have left me do have matayned &amp;
                    <lb/>my pore children lawfully begotten by him of my body but having one 
                    <lb/>wife before he maryed me by whome he has also children hath made 
                    <lb/>such provision in his will as the within mencioned that if the
                    <lb/>humble petition should chance to <unclear reason="illegible">marry</unclear> that which I was forced to do
                    <lb/>otherways was not able to maintain myself and change my deceased husband
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> Ashbrooke lifetime that then I should not have any part or parcell of
                    <lb/>the Land to love on during my life but immediately upon that
                    <lb/>deliver the Land unto his sonne James Ashbrooke as your hon. may
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> by the within mentioned will that which if we are forced to
                    <lb/>doe we are utterly ruined not having any <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> place to <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                    <lb/>and worke to mentain our therefore we the said temperance-
                    <lb/>Ashbrooke alias Clowder &amp; Richard Clowder her now husband humbly 
                    <lb/>beegs your hon. of your inward woth Clemency and <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> will
                    <lb/>be pleased to grant them liberty of administration in the right of her
                    <lb/>thirds or as your hon. thinks fitt both the said temperance &amp; the
                    <lb/>said Richard by these presence renouncing teh said will under their 
                    <lb/>hands the <date>22nd day of August 1678</date>. And they as in duly bound shall
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> pray of your hon.
                    <lb/>9 sides
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>