<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="MD_CC_PRO_051_1676_Anderson" xml:lang="en">John Anderson. Will.</title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <author></author>
                <editor>Emily Boyer</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Signed Sealed Delivered</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)">John Anderson. Will.</head>
                <p>In the name of God Amen I <persName type="author">John <surname>Anderson</surname></persName> of <placeName>Charles County in
                <lb/>Potucent River</placeName> planter being sick &amp; weake but of perfect minde and memory have
                    <lb/>thought it fit to set my worldy business in order as followeth
                </p>
                <p>Itm. Forst I dou bequeath my soule to the Almighty God who have me my first
                    <lb/>being secondly my body to the ground and thirdly I doue truly give and
                    <lb/>bequeath unto my dear wife <persName type="spouse" xml:id="MaryAnderson">Mary <surname>Anderson</surname></persName> and the child that she now goes
                    <lb/>wihtall if it liveth all my whole personal Estate that I have in this world and 
                    <lb/>the land and plantation that I now live upon with the appointmenses there
                    <lb/>belongng unto it after my dates in paud it is my will and pleasure that all
                    <lb/>my personal Estate is to be equally divided between my dear wife and child
                    <lb/>if it pleaseth the Lord that is doath and as for the plantation I now live upon
                    <lb/>if my child liveth then after the deth of my dear wife then it shall enjoy it
                    <lb/>it if bee mayle or female and see to
                    <lb/>and if the child should should dyethen all the personal Estate to fall to my dear
                    <lb/>wife for <unclear reason="illegible">wer more</unclear> it is my will and pleasure that if the child thereth <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> dear
                    <lb/>as my dear wife nomaimith all <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> that she may have the whole <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> of the
                    <lb/>Estate but when she maryes then if the man that she shall marieth shall <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                    <lb/>wayes bee <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> awaye or <unclear reason="illegible">consume</unclear> the Estate then the appointed overseers shall <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                    <lb/>away the child Estate and of he shall any wayes above the Child they shall take
                    <lb/>the child Estate and his Estate and if he shall any wayes above the Child they shall take
                    <lb/>my well and pleasure that the Child should bee brought up to living- in the
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible">fear</unclear> of the Lord <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> I dsire and trust and appoint my to well beloved friends to
                    <lb/>look carefully after this my will to see it houly performed in all <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> 
                    <lb/>whereforth forever. I doue <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> <persName type="overseer" xml:id="WilliamJenkins">Mr. William <surname>Jenkins</surname></persName> and my dear brother 
                    <lb/><persName type="brother" xml:id="RobertDent">Robert <surname>Dent</surname></persName> given under my hand and seal this first day <date>march anno
                    <lb/>thousand six hundred seventy and five</date>.
                </p>
                <p><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">William <surname>Wade</surname></persName>-<persName type="witness">Henry Norman</persName>-<signatures>John Anderson</signatures>
                </p>
                    <pb/>
               <p>On the back of the foregoing was the following Endorsement to wit
                   <lb/><persName type="witness">William <surname>Head</surname></persName> and Henry Norman both witnesses of the said will and Both
                   <lb/>sumon before me this <date>seventeenth day of July in the year 1676</date>.
                   <lb/><signatures>Willm. <surname>Groome</surname></signatures>
               </p>
                <p>Mary Anderson The Executor swrone before ths <date>17th July in the
                <lb/>year 1676</date>.
                <lb/>4 sides.
                    <lb/><persName>Willm. <surname>Groome</surname></persName>
                    
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>