<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="MD_CC_PRO_043_1675_Mathens" xml:lang="en">Thomas Matt</title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <author></author>
                <editor></editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Signed Sealed Delivered</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)"><!-- John Smith. Will --></head>
                <p>In the Name of God Amen. This ninth day of January ano. One thousand 
                    <lb/>Six hundred and seventy five and  in the 44th year of the Dominion of the right 
                    <lb/>honorable [Cecilius] absolute Lord and proprietor of the province of Maryland I Thomas 
                    <lb/>[Mathens] of Charles County in the province of aforesaid [Gentry?] being sick and weake 
                    <lb/>in body but of sound and perfect memory praise be to god for the same and 
                    <lb/>Knowing the uncertainty of this life and being
                    <lb/>the uncertainty of this life and being desirous to sell <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> things in order doe
                    <lb/>make this my last will and testament in manner and form following that is to say
                    <lb/>first and principally I comend my soule to god my creator <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> believing that
                    <lb/>I shall recieve full pardon and <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> of all my sins and be saved by the
                    <lb/>precious Death and merits of our beloved Savior and reademer Christ Jesus
                    <lb/>and my body to the earth from where it came to be buried in such decent and
                    <lb/>Christian manner as to my Execturos thereafter named shall be thought <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> and
                    <lb/>Convenient and as touching such wordle Estate as god hath lent me my will
                    <lb/>and meaning is the same shall be imformed and bestowed as hereafter by this
                    <lb/>my will is <unclear reason="illegible">exchanged</unclear> and first and principally. I do will and require that all
                    <lb/>my Just Debts be truly satisfied discharged and paid and I doe hereby revoke
                    <lb/>renounce <unclear reason="illegible">frustrait</unclear> and make void all wills by me formely made ad declare
                    <lb/>and appoint this my last will and testament.
                </p>
                <p><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> I givr and bequeath unto my wife <placeName type="spouse">Jane <unclear reason="illegible"><surname>Mathuse</surname></unclear></placeName> my holl personal Estate that is at
                    <lb/><placeName>Port Tobacco</placeName> that is to say all manner of things for the good of her and my childring
                    <lb/>and I do give and bequeath to her my wife <measure commodity="land" quantity="300" unit="acre">Three hundred acres of Land called the
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible">Lunchelbury Swamp</unclear></measure> or <unclear reason="illegible">bulky </unclear> lying in <placeName>Charles County</placeName> and I give and bequeath
                    <lb/>to my son <persName type="son">Thomas <surname>Mathens</surname></persName> <measure commodity="land" quantity="700" unit="acre">Seven hundred acres of land</measure> being part of a thousand
                    <lb/>acres of Land lying upon Matawoman branches and that he have that part
                    <lb/>which he hath already sealed upon and I give to my D. Capt. Bormans wife
                    <lb/><measure commodity="land" quantity="300" unit="acre">three hundred acres of land</measure> which is the remainder of that I give my son Thomas
                    <lb/>and to him and his heirs forever and to her heirs forever I do alsoe give
                    <lb/><catchwords>and</catchwords>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>and bequeath to my son Thomas Mathens and to my D. after <persName type="daughter">Mary 
                    <lb/><surname>Borman</surname></persName> <measure commodity="land" quantity="255" unit="acre">two hundred and fifty five acres of Land</measure> lying at <placeName>St. Maries
                    <lb/>Hill</placeName> threshold <unclear reason="illegible">Early</unclear> to be divided between them to them and their heirs
                    <lb/>forever and I give to my wife Jane Mathews <measure commodity="land" quantity="400" unit="acre">four hundred acres of
                    <lb/>Land</measure> lying at Capt. Bonman three cows and three yearling calved and five
                    <lb/>stears about four years of that belongs to the plantation of <placeName>S. Ellins</placeName>
                    <lb/>and to my wife I give and bequeath all the other things that belongs to
                    <lb/>the said plantation of <placeName>St. Ellins</placeName> that is Tobacco Debts or other things
                    <lb/>whatsoever that shall be due to mee. and I doe further make Constitute
                    <lb/>and afront m head and loving wife Jane Mathews my Executor to see
                    <lb/>this my will performed but if in Case my wife should dy before me then
                    <lb/>it is my will that my son Thomas Mathews and <persName type="son-in-law">Capt. William Borman</persName>
                    <lb/>be Executor of this my will to see it performed in testimony and witness
                    <lb/>whereof I have hereunto set my hand and seal this day and year above
                    <lb/>said
                    <lb/><signatures><persName type="witness">Ignatius Causen</persName></signatures>
                    <lb/>his
                    <lb/><signatures><persName type="witness">Marke W Lamson</persName>.</signatures>
                    <lb/>mark
                    <lb/><signatures>Tho. Mathews</signatures>
                </p>
                <p>On the back of the aforegoing will was the following probit to <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                    <lb/><date>March the 11th 1675</date> This day Came before me before me Ignatius Causen and Mark
                    <lb/>Lamson and made oath that they saw the said Mr. Thomas Mathews sign
                    <lb/>seal and deliver this as his last will and testament as witness our hands
                    <lb/>and seals.
                </p>
                <p>Sworn before me this 11 of March
                   <lb/><signatures><persName>Henry <surname>Adams</surname></persName></signatures>
                    <lb/>6 1/4 sides
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>