<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="xx" xml:lang="en"><!-- Title ex. John Smith. Will --></title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <author></author>
                <editor></editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Signed Sealed Delivered</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)"><!-- John Smith. Will --></head>
                <p>In the name of God Amen, this twenty fourth day of December anno 1672
                <lb/>I <persName type="author">Matthew <surname>Stone</surname></persName> of <placeName>Charles County in the province of Maryland</placeName> planter being sick of 
                <lb/>body but of good and perfect memory thanks bee to God and calling to mind 
                <lb/>the <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> Estate of this transitory life and that all flesh must yield unto
                <lb/><catchwords>Death</catchwords>
                    
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>Death [unknown] it shall please God to call do make Constitute ordaine and 
                    Declare this to bee my last will and testament in manner and form 
                    Following First being [pertinant?] and [unclear] from the bottom of my heart 
                    For my [sens?] past humbly desiring forgiveness for the same I give and 
                    Commit my soule unto Allmighty God my savior and redeemer in 
                    whome and by the merits of Jesus Christ Death and passion 
                    [unclear] and inherit the Kingdom of Heaven prepared for his Elect and 
                    [Chosen?] amd my body to bee buried in such place where it shall please my
                    Executors hereafter named to appoint, and for the settleing of my temporal 
                    Estate. I do order give disperse of the same in manner and form following 
                    That is to say first I will that all those Debts which I owe in right or 
                    [Conocieve?] to any manner of person or persons whatsoever shall be well 
                    And truly satisfied contented and paid in som Convenient time after my 
                    [unclear] by my Executor hereafter named.
                    
               
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>