<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="MD_CC_PRO_062_1674_7_Corsellton" xml:lang="en">Robert Corsellton Will</title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <editor>Emily Boyer</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>"Maryland, Register of Wills Records, 1629-1999." 
                    Images. FamilySearch. <ref target="http://FamilySearch.org">http://FamilySearch.org</ref>: 3 December 2024. 
                    Citing Prerogative Court. Hall of Records, Annapolis.</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p><ref><!-- link to primary source here --></ref></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)">Robert Corsellton Will</head>
                <p>In the name of God Amen. The <date>sixth day of January
                <lb/>one thousand six hundred seventy and four</date> I <persName type="author">Robert <surname>Corsellton</surname></persName> of
                    <lb/><placeName>Charles County in the provinence of Maryland</placeName> being sick and weake in
                    <lb/>body but of good and perfect memory thanks bee to God knowing 
                    <lb/>that I am naturally Borne and ordained to die and considering the
                    <lb/>uncertaintee of this life on earth doe make this my last will and
                    <lb/>testament in manner and form following first I bequeath my soule
                    <lb/>and I <unclear reason="illegible">peritt</unclear> into the hands of almighty God my heavenly father by whome
                    <lb/>of his <unclear reason="illegible">mure</unclear> grace and favour I trust to be reveived into eternal rest through
                    <lb/><catchwords>the</catchwords>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>the Death of my sweet saviour Jesus Christ in whose precious blood
                    <lb/>I <unclear reason="illegible">set</unclear> the only hope of my <unclear reason="illegible">satuatione</unclear> my wreched body in hope of
                    <lb/>a Joyfull resurection I commit to the earth to be decently buried by
                    <lb/>my Executors hereafter named and touching the distruition of my
                    <lb/>mortal goods, I disphose as followeth. First I will that all my
                    <lb/>Just Debts shall be honestly paid.
                </p>
                <p>Item I make Constitute and appoint <persName type="spouse" xml:id="MaryCorsellton">Mary</persName> my wife my sole Executor    
                </p>
                <p>Item. I give and bequeath unto my sonne <persName type="son" xml:id="RobertCorsellton">Robert</persName> <measure commodity="land" quantity="150" unit="acre" xml:id="RobertCorsellton">one hundred and fifty
                <lb/>acres of land called <name>York</name></measure> if said son Robert shall due without an
                    <lb/>heir then the said land shall fall to my sonne <persName type="son" xml:id="JohnCorsellton">John</persName> if my sone John
                    <lb/>shall dye without heir then the said land shall fall to my Daughter
                    <lb/><persName type="daughter" xml:id="DaughterMary">Mary</persName> and her heirs forever.
                </p>
                <p>Item I give and bequeath to my sone John after the Decease of Mary my wife
                    <lb/><measure commodity="plantation" xml:id="JohnCorsellton">my plantation and land called <name>Naping</name></measure> if my sone John should
                    <lb/>die without an heir then the said land and plantation shall fall
                    <lb/>to my sone Robert if my son Robert shall dye without heirs then the
                    <lb/>said land plantation shall fall unto my Daughter Mary and her heris 
                    <lb/>forever Lastlt I doe make and appoint my said children and their Estates
                    <lb/>untill they come to age and I doe utterly revoke all wills by me <unclear reason="illegible">fornesly</unclear>
                    <lb/>made either by word or writing and declare this to be my last will
                    <lb/>and testament in witness hereof I have hereunto set my hand and seal
                </p>
                <p>Signed Sealed and Delivered
                    <lb/>In the presense of us
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">Thomas <surname>Jenkins</surname></persName> - <persName>George <surname>Longham</surname></persName>
                <lb/>his
                    <lb/>Robert Corsellton
                    <lb/>mark
                </p>
                <p>On the back of the aforegoing will was Endorsed the foll. probate <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                    <lb/><date>May 21st. 1678</date> Then was this will proved in common form
                    <lb/>by the oaths of George Longham and Thomas Jenkins witnesses to
                    <lb/>the same - before me
                    <lb/>4 1/4 sides
                    <lb/><persName>Benjamin Rozer</persName>
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>