<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="MD_CC_PRO_063_1677_8_King" xml:lang="en">Thomas King Will</title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <editor>Emily Boyer</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>"Maryland, Register of Wills Records, 1629-1999." 
                    Images. FamilySearch. <ref target="http://FamilySearch.org">http://FamilySearch.org</ref>: 3 December 2024. 
                    Citing Prerogative Court. Hall of Records, Annapolis.</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p><ref><!-- link to primary source here --></ref></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)">Thomas King Will</head>
                <p>1st In the name of God Amen. I <persName type="author">Thomas <surname>King</surname></persName> of <placeName>Charles County
                <lb/>in the province of Maryland</placeName> being very sick and weake in body but <unclear reason="illegible">blessed</unclear>
                    <lb/>be the Lord having my perfect sence and memory doe make here my
                    <lb/>last will and testament. First I do give and bequeath unto Almighty my 
                    <lb/>soule that made it and my body to a Christian burial and all my wordly
                    <lb/>goods as followeth after my Debts be satisfied.
                </p>
                <p>2nd I doe give and bequeath unto my wifes Eldest D after <persName type="step-daughter" xml:id="ElizabethJohnes">Elizabeth <surname>Johnes</surname></persName> <measure commodity="horse" quantity="2" xml:id="ElizabethJones">two
                <lb/>mares</measure> and <measure commodity="livestock" quantity="4" xml:id="ElizabethJohnes">four caves</measure>. 
                </p>
                <p>3rd I doe give unto my wives onee <persName type="step-son" xml:id="PhilipJohnes">Philip <surname>Johnes</surname></persName> <measure commodity="horse" quantity="1" xml:id="PhilipJones">one mare filly about two
                    <lb/>4 years of age</measure> 4 by I doe bequeath unto <persName type="niece" xml:id="MaryRider">Mary <surname>Rider</surname></persName> and <persName type="niece" xml:id="SusanaFogg">Susana
                    <lb/><surname>Fogg</surname></persName> the D <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> of my Deceased sister <persName type="sister">Susana <surname>Fogg</surname></persName> wife of <persName type="brother-in-law">David <surname>Fogg</surname></persName>
                    <lb/><measure type="land" quantity="25" unit="acre" xml:id="MaryRider">twenty and five acres of Land</measure> now in the hand and possession of <persName>Margaret 
                    <lb/><surname>Cutter</surname></persName> with all the rights and priviledges there and belonging unto the
                    <lb/>said Mary and Susana and there heirs forever and also my brother
                    <lb/>David Fogg to be their gardian untill they be married or sixteen years
                    <lb/>years of age and if in case one of them should dye without heirs that 
                    <lb/>then it is to fall to their cosen Elizabeth Johnes and her heirs.
                </p>
                <p>5 I doe give and bequeath unto <persName type="unbornchild" xml:id="unbornchlid">my child my wife goeth with</persName> now my
                    <lb/>will at <unclear reason="illegible">nonsingy</unclear> and <measure commodity="livestock" quantity="10" xml:id="unbornchild">ten caves</measure> also and in case the child shall come to
                    <lb/>life twelve years of age that therein the child lad or mayde shall have the
                    <lb/>the full disporsing of the will and cattle also whatsoever falleth to my wife
                    <lb/>after Leggasies givwn and debts paid in case my wife deith before my 
                    <lb/>Child be twelve years ould that what falleth to her then shall be given
                    <lb/>to the aforesaid child at twelve years of age for its desposiall and in care
                    <lb/>my wife shall live tillafter the child be twelve years of age that she
                    <lb/>shall then enjoy what falleth to her her life time and after my wife
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible">J</unclear> - Decease that then what belongeth to her shall fall to my
                    <lb/><catchwords>wifes</catchwords>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>wifes three children I doe give also to <persName type="beneficiary" xml:id="GeorgeNuemanJunior">George <surname>Nueman</surname> Senior</persName> <measure commodity="food" xml:id="GeorgeNuemanJunior">six
                    <lb/>Barells of <unclear reason="illegible">corn</unclear></measure> and Last I doe give <persName type="beneficiary" xml:id="JohnWheeler">John <surname>Wheeler</surname></persName> of <placeName><unclear reason="illegible">Nonounoie</unclear></placeName>
                    <lb/><measure commodity="crop" quantity="300" unit="pounds">three hundred pounds of Tobacco</measure> to be the year next insuing and to 
                    <lb/>the <unclear reason="illegible">primises</unclear> above given and mentioned I have hereunto set
                    <lb/>my hand and seal the <date>17th day of January and in the y year
                    <lb/>of our Lord 1677</date>. Signed Sealed and delivered in presense of us
                    <lb/>it is to be understood that the Land given to my sister Susanas
                    <lb/>children my wife <persName type="spouse" xml:id="JohanathKing">Johanath <surname>King</surname></persName> is to enjoy it for four years
                    <lb/>after the day and date hereof and then to fall and be delivered unto 
                    <lb/>my brother David Fogg as gardian unto the children aforesaid 
                </p>
                <p>Signed Sealed and Delivered
                    <lb/>In presence of
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">John <surname>Douglass</surname></persName> - <persName type="witness">Richard Edeling</persName>
                    <lb/>Thomas King 
                    <lb/>signn
                </p>
                <p>On he back of the aforegoing will was endorsed the foll. probate to will,
                    <lb/><date>August 15th 1678</date>. There was the within written will proved
                    <lb/>in common form by the oaths of John Douglass and Richard Edeling
                    <lb/>before me commissioned thereto
                    <lb/>5 1/4 sides
                    <lb/><persName>Benjamin Rozer</persName>
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>