<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="MD_CC_PRO_045_1675_Dickeson" xml:lang="en">Jeremiah Dickeson Will.</title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <author></author>
                <editor>Emily Boyer</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Signed Sealed and Delivered</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)">Jeremiah Dickeson Will.</head>
                <p>In the name of God Amen. The <date>twenty ninth day of September in the year of our 
                    <lb/>Lord one Thousand six hundred and seventy three</date> I <persName type="author">Jeremiah Dickeson</persName> of <placeName>Charles County</placeName>
                    <lb/>thanks be to God for the fame and calling to remembrance the uncertain Estate of
                    <lb/>this Transitory life and  that all flesh must yeild unto Death when it shall please 
                    <lb/>God to call those make Constitute Ordaine and Declare this my last will and
                    <lb/>Testament in manner and form following reworking and adnulling by these <unclear reason="illegible">preats</unclear>
                    <lb/>all and every Testament &amp; Testament will &amp; wills theretofore by me made &amp; declared
                    <lb/>either by word or writing and this is to be taken for my last will &amp; Testament &amp;
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> other and first being <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> &amp; sorry from the bottom of my heart for my sins
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> most humbly desiring forgiveness for the same I give and commit my soule unto
                    <lb/>Almighty God my savoiur and redeemer in whome and by the merits of Jesus
                    <lb/>Christ and believe <unclear reason="illegible">apuredly</unclear> to be saved &amp; to have full <unclear reason="illegible">reunification</unclear> &amp; forgiveness of sins 
                    <lb/>and that my soule with my body all the general day of reunification shall use againe
                    <lb/>with Joy and through the merits of Christs Death and passion <unclear reason="illegible">profits</unclear> and inheret the
                    <lb/>Kingdom of heaven prepared for the Eleet and chosen and my body to be buried in such 
                    <lb/>place whereit shall please my Estate &amp; such goods Chattle &amp; debts as it hath pleased god for
                    <lb/>above my desents to bestow whom me I doe give and displease of the same in manner
                    <lb/>&amp; form following that is to say first I will that all those Debts &amp; <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> that I have in
                    <lb/>right or conceive to all manner of person or persons whatsoever shall be well and
                    <lb/>truly Contented &amp; paid on Ordaine to be paid weither Convenient Time after my
                    <lb/>decrease by my Executor hereafter named.
                </p>
                <p>Item I give and bequeath to my Godaughter <persName type="goddaughter" xml:id="ElizabethHarrison">Elizabeth <surname>Harrison</surname></persName> <measure commodity="livestock" quantity="1" xml:id="ElizabethHarrison">one cow calf</measure> to be delivered
                    <lb/><catchwords>to</catchwords>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>to her the next spring after my Decease.
                </p>
                <p>Item. I give and bequeath unto each of my servants <measure commodity="livestock" quantity="1"></measure>one cow and calf to be delivered to them as they are free.
                </p>
                <p>Item. I give and bequeath unto my Loving friend <persName><unclear reason="illegible" xml:id="Leche">Leche</unclear></persName> <surname>Greene</surname> <measure commodity="crop" quantity="400" unit="pounds" xml:id="Leche">four hundred pounds
                <lb/>of tobacco &amp; <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear></measure>.
                </p>
                <p>Item. I give and bequeath all the rest of my Estate both real and personal to my
                    <lb/>Sonne <persName type="son" xml:id="ThomasDickeson">Thomas <surname>Dickeson</surname></persName> to him and his heirs forever whome I wil &amp; desire my
                    <lb/>be brought up and be at the <unclear reason="illegible">tuition</unclear> of my Executors hereafter named until
                    <lb/>he come to the age of three &amp; twenty years &amp; not to enjoy the Estate before
                    <lb/>and after the he shall not sell or anywise make away with the Land but
                    <lb/>shall fall to the heris begotten lawfully of his body which if he die wihtout
                  <lb/>or before he come to the foresaid age I give and bequeath the personal Estate
                    <lb/>unto my <unclear reason="illegible">trusty</unclear> &amp; well loved friend <persName type="executor" xml:id="ThomasDent">Mr. Thomas Dent</persName> of <placeName>S. Maries County</placeName>
                    <lb/>and <persName type="executor" xml:id="NicholasProddly">Mr. Nicholas Proddly</persName> of <placeName>Charles County</placeName> whome also I nominate ordaine &amp;
                    <lb/>appoint Executors and overseers of this my lasy will &amp; testament and my
                    <lb/>Land and I give unto the poore of <placeName>Charles County</placeName> to be dispersed of and ordered at the
                    <lb/>dispersion of my foresaid Executors &amp; it is my desire that my said sonne Thomas
                    <lb/>Dickeson be right two years at school &amp; afterwards brought up to worke asfore
                    <lb/>named Executor shall think <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> he being seventeene years of age at Easter <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                    <lb/>after the date hereafter In Testimony whereof I have to this my last will &amp; testament 
                    <lb/>put my hand &amp; seal the day &amp; year first above written
                </p>
                <p>Signed &amp; sealed
                    <lb/>In the presence of us
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">John <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> <surname>Gray</surname></persName>-<persName type="witness">Matter his M <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear></persName>
                    <lb/>mark 
                </p>
                <p>On the back of the aforegoing was the following Endorsements (to will)
                    <lb/>Maryland <unclear reason="illegible">Js.</unclear> By virtue of a commission from the Judge for probate of
                    <lb/>wills and granting administration wiithin the province to me directed 
                    <lb/>and me Im proving bearing date the <date>20th day of April in the 48th year
                    <lb/>of the Dominion of Cecelius &amp;c anno Dom. 1675</date> I called before me <unclear reason="illegible">Matter</unclear>
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> &amp; John Gray two witness to the within written will who proved the
                    <lb/>same in common form in the <date>14th day of may 1675</date>.
                    <lb/><persName>Benjamin <surname>Rozer</surname></persName>               
                </p>
                <pb/>
                <p>By Virtue of the Commission above mentioned on the <date>14th day of May <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                    <lb/>1675</date> I administrated by the Oath of an Executor unto Nicholas Brody ono
                    <lb/>of the Executor Named in the within written will According to the form
                    <lb/>in the saif Commission <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                    <lb/><signatures>Benj. Roger</signatures>
                </p>
                <p><date>May 14th 1675</date>
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible">Then</unclear> administered the Oath of <unclear reason="illegible">springer</unclear> to <persName>Zachariah <surname>Wade</surname></persName> &amp; <persName>John <surname>Ward</surname></persName>, to
                    <lb/>appraise the Estate of Jeremiah Dickeson Decreased by Virue of a Commission 
                    <lb/>from the Judge in testontary cause. to me <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> Dated the <date>20th of April
                        <lb/>1675</date>
                    <lb/>8 1/4 sides
                    <lb/>Benjamin Rozer
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>