<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="xx" xml:lang="en"><!-- Title ex. John Smith. Will --></title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <author></author>
                <editor></editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Signed Sealed Delivered</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)"><!-- John Smith. Will --></head>
                <p>In the name of the Lord God Everlasting Amen. I <persName type="author">Alexander
                    <lb/><surname>Simpson</surname></persName> of <placeName>Port Tobacco in the province of Maryland</placeName> planter being at this 
                    <lb/>present time very sick and weak but of sound and perfect memory <unclear reason="illegible">blessed</unclear> be 
                    <lb/>God for the same do make appoint and ordain to be my last will 
                    <lb/>and testament hereby <unclear reason="illegible">working</unclear> <unclear reason="illegible">Disannulling</unclear> &amp; making void all other will 
                    <lb/>and testemenat by me thereforeafter made either by word or writing 
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible">following</unclear> &amp; ordaining this sole my lasy will and testament and no other 
                    <lb/>whatsoever.
                </p>
                <p>I <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> commint my soul into the hand of God that gave it hoping through 
                    <lb/>the <unclear reason="illegible">miracle</unclear> of my dear Lord and savior Jesus Christ for a glorious resurrection 
                    <lb/>and my body to the ground to buried in decent manner according to the 
                    <lb/>will &amp; discussion of my <unclear reason="illegible">Executor</unclear> underneath specified and for all my 
                    <lb/>worldly goods I do give and bequeath them in manner and form following
                    <lb/>after my <unclear reason="illegible">true</unclear> and lawful debts that I have to any person or persons <unclear reason="illegible">be</unclear>will
                    <lb/>and truly paid satisfied &amp; discharged.
                    <pb/>
                </p>
                <p>Item I do fully &amp; bequeath unto my God Daughter <persName type="goddaughter">Margret <surname>Mahol</surname></persName> daughter of <persName><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>Arehball
                <lb/></persName>
                    Wahol all that dividend or parcel of land lying between her fathers plantation
                    and the plantation that I now live upon by estimation one hundred and
                    twenty acres to have and to hould to her and her heirs forever but if the said
                    Margrett Mahol die without heirs lawfully begotten of her body then I do give 
                    the above said hundred twenty acres of land to her sister Elizabeth Mahol 
                    to have &amp; to hould to her and her heirs forever. 
                    
                    
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>