<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="MD_CC_PRO_039_1669_Simpsons" xml:lang="en">Alexander Simpsons Will</title>
                
                <author></author>
                <editor></editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Signed Sealed Delivered</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)">Alexander Simpsons Will</head>
                <p>In the name of the Lord God Everlasting Amen. I <persName type="author">Alexander
                    <lb/><surname>Simpson</surname></persName> of <placeName>Port Tobacco in the province of Maryland</placeName> planter being at this 
                    <lb/>present time very sick and weak but of sound and perfect memory <unclear reason="illegible">blessed</unclear> be 
                    <lb/>God for the same do make appoint and ordain to be my last will 
                    <lb/>and testament hereby <unclear reason="illegible">working</unclear> <unclear reason="illegible">Disannulling</unclear> &amp; making void all other will 
                    <lb/>and testemenat by me thereforeafter made either by word or writing 
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible">following</unclear> &amp; ordaining this sole my lasy will and testament and no other 
                    <lb/>whatsoever.
                </p>
                <p>I <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> commint my soul into the hand of God that gave it hoping through 
                    <lb/>the <unclear reason="illegible">miracle</unclear> of my dear Lord and savior Jesus Christ for a glorious resurrection 
                    <lb/>and my body to the ground to buried in decent manner according to the 
                    <lb/>will &amp; discussion of my <unclear reason="illegible">Executor</unclear> underneath specified and for all my 
                    <lb/>worldly goods I do give and bequeath them in manner and form following
                    <lb/>after my <unclear reason="illegible">true</unclear> and lawful debts that I have to any person or persons <unclear reason="illegible">be</unclear>will
                    <lb/>and truly paid satisfied &amp; discharged.
                    <pb/>
                </p>
                <p>Item I do fully &amp; bequeath unto my God Daughter <persName type="goddaughter">Margret <surname>Wahol</surname></persName> daughter of <persName><unclear reason="illegible">Archball</unclear> Wahol</persName>
                <lb/>all that dividend or parcel of land lying between her fathers plantation
                <lb/>and the plantation that I now live upon by estimation <measure commodity="land" quantity="120" unit="acre">one hundred and
                 <lb/>twenty acres</measure> to have and to hould to her and her heirs forever but if the said
                <lb/>Margrett Mahol die without heirs lawfully begotten of her body then I do give 
                <lb/>the above said hundred twenty acres of land to her sister <persName type="beneficiary">Elizabeth <surname>Wahol</surname></persName>
                <lb/>to have &amp; to hould to her and her heirs forever. 
                </p>
                <p>Itm. I do freely bequeat and give until Elizabeth Wahol Daughter of Mr. Arehball Wahol
                    <lb/>my now dwelling home orchard and other houses with that parcel of land 
                    <lb/>belonging to it houlden and <unclear reason="illegible">refuted</unclear> <measure commodity="land" quantity="120" unit="acre">one hundred and twenty acres</measure> be it 
                    <lb/>more or less lying between said parcel of land given to her sister 
                    <lb/>Margrett Wahol &amp; the land of <persName>John <surname>Paine</surname></persName> to have &amp; to hould to her and her 
                    <lb/>heirs forever but if the said Elizabeth shall die without heirs lawfully begotten 
                    <lb/>of her body then I do give it to her sister Margrett and her heirs forever
                    <lb/>(provided also) that if the two above mentioned sisters Margrett &amp; Elizabeth 
                    <lb/>Mahol shall happen to due in their minoritye then I do feely give the <measure commodity="land" quantity="200" unit="acre">two hundred parcels 
                    <lb/>of land</measure> above <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> given to them unto <persName type="beneficiary">Mrs. Jane <surname>Wahol</surname></persName> wife of Arehball 
                    <lb/>Mahol their mother to her to have &amp; to hould or to disperse at will &amp; pleasure forever 
                    <lb/>Itm. I give &amp; bequeath unto <persName type="beneficiary">Jacob Leah</persName> Brother of Mrs. Jane Mahol <measure type="plantation" quantity="300" unit="acre">all the parcel of land
                    <lb/>Called Sampson <unclear reason="illegible">delight</unclear> by Estimation three hundred acres</measure> situated lying and 
                    <lb/>being on the west side near the head of <placeName>Portobacho Creek</placeName> to have &amp; to hould to him 
                    <lb/>and his heirs forever. <unclear reason="faded">Next two sentences are rendered unclear because of fading</unclear>
                    <lb/>Itm. I do give and bequeath until Mr. Archball Wahol <measure commodity="horse" quantity="1">one yearling black coult</measure> with 
                    <lb/>a small star in his fore head. Item I do give &amp; bequeath unto my goddaughter Margarett Wahol
                    <lb/><measure commodity="houseware" quantity="1" unit="silver">one silver boule</measure> and <measure commodity="flatware" quantity="12" unit="silver">one dozen silver spoons</measure>. 
                </p>
                <p>Itm. I do give and bequeath unto <persName type="beneficiary">Thomas <surname><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>Corben</surname></persName> <measure commodity="weapon" quantity="1"></measure>my sword &amp; <measure type="clothing" quantity="1"></measure>belt and for the over sight 
                    <lb/>and true performance of what is expressed in this testament I do hereby make 
                    <lb/>ordaine and constitute my truly and well beloved neighbour Mrs. Jane Wahol 
                    <lb/>not above specified I do truly give them to my said Executirs and her two 
                    <lb/>Daughters Margrett &amp; Elizabeth to be equally divided amongst them and now
                    <lb/><catchwords>I do</catchwords>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>I do and desire that this and no other may be houlden taken &amp; refuted 
                    <lb/>my last will &amp; testament &amp; no other <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> whereof I have set to my hand
                    <lb/>&amp; seal this <date>3rd day of December 1669</date>.
                    <lb/>his mark
                    <lb/><signatures rend="align(right)">Alexander AS Simpson</signatures>
                </p>
                <p><date>December 30th 1669</date>
                    <lb/>This last will and testament within write was designed &amp; sealed by Alexander 
                    <lb/>Simpson &amp; <unclear reason="illegible">duland</unclear> by him to be his last will &amp; testament in the presents of 
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">Humphrey <surname>Manner</surname></persName>
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">Alexander <surname><unclear reason="illegible">Gattent</unclear></surname></persName>
                    <lb/><persName type="witness"><unclear reason="illegible">Gonnell</unclear> <surname>Williams</surname></persName>
                </p>
                    <p>On the back was the following <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> Endorsed to will
                    <lb/><date>April 12th 1670</date> the within written will &amp; testament of Alexander Simpson was 
                    <lb/>by the oath of Humphrey Manner &amp; Alexander Gallent witnessed thereunto in 
                    <lb/>Common form proved before me. 
                    <lb/>7 ¾ sides 
                    </p> 
                    
              
                
                    
                    
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>