<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="MD_CC_PRO_058_1676_Roberts" xml:lang="en">Edward Roberts Will</title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <author></author>
                <editor>Emily Boyer</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Signed Sealed and Delivered</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)">Edward Roberts Will</head>
                <p>In the name of God Amen. I <persName type="author">Edward <surname>Roberts</surname></persName> of <placeName>Charles County in the
                    <lb/>province of Maryland</placeName> being sick in body in perfect sense and memory
                    <lb/>thanks to Almighty God do ordaine and make this my last will and 
                    <lb/>testament in presense of followeth first I beque my soule to god hoping through
                    <lb/>his blessed Death and passion that he will have mercy upon my soule and
                    <lb/>Receive me into his heavenly kingdom and what small estate that that god
                    <lb/>has been pleased to bestow apon me I am willing it should be dispersed
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> as foleth I give and beque all my astate both reall and parsonall unto unto
                    <lb/><persName type="beneficiary" xml:id="CharlesAllenson">Charles <surname>Allenson</surname></persName> and <persName type="beneficiary" xml:id="ElizabethAllenson">Elizabeth <surname>Allenson</surname></persName> son and Daughter to <persName type="beneficiary" xml:id="ThomasAllenson">Thomas <surname>Allenson</surname></persName>
                    <lb/>of <placeName>Charles County in the province of Maryland</placeName> and the said Tho. Allenson
                    <lb/>father to the said Charles Allenson and Elizabeth to be hole and sole Executor
                    <lb/>of this my lasy will and testament in the said children behalf or any
                    <lb/>money that is folen to me in England by the Death of an <unclear reason="illegible">unhell</unclear> <persName type="beneficiary" xml:id="JohnRud">John 
                    <lb/><surname>Rud</surname></persName> sun to my grand Father <persName>George</persName> unintellegable  as by the said
                    <lb/>grand father will will apear and I do further ordaine this my last
                    <lb/>will and testament trusting and making voyd all former wills by me
                    <lb/>mad and for this my last will and testament to I hope in my mercy of god
                    <lb/>that he will arrive- my soule and for the have performance I have hearunto
                    <lb/>set my hand and seal this <date>fifteen day of January 1676</date>.
                </p>
                <p>Signed Sealed and Delivered
                <lb/>In the presence of us
                <lb/>his
                <lb/>John Belley 
                <lb/>his
                <lb/>Martha W Browne
                <lb/>mark
                    <lb/>William Boyne
                    <lb/>Edward Roberts
                </p>
                <pb/>
                <p>On the back of the foregoing will was the following probate Endorsed (to will)
                    <lb/><date>November 22d. 1677</date>.
                </p>
                <p>The deposition of William Boydon and John Belley saith that this is the
                    <lb/>last will and testament of Edward Roberts of <placeName>Charles County</placeName> desed
                    <lb/>and was his oath and deed and further saith noth sworn before me
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">Zachary <surname>Wade</surname></persName> as it doth appear by my hand and seal
                    <lb/>3 1/4 sides
                    <lb/>Zachary Wade
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>