<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="MD_CC_PRO_061_1677_Wade" xml:lang="en">Zachary Wade Will</title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <editor>Emily Boyer</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>"Maryland, Register of Wills Records, 1629-1999." 
                    Images. FamilySearch. <ref target="http://FamilySearch.org">http://FamilySearch.org</ref>: 3 December 2024. 
                    Citing Prerogative Court. Hall of Records, Annapolis.</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)">Zachary Wade Will</head>
                <p>In the name of God Amen. I <persName type="author">Zachary <surname>Wade</surname></persName> of <placeName>Charles
                <lb/>County in the province of Maryland</placeName> Gentl. being suck in body but of
                    <lb/>perfect minde and memory prasied bee to God for the same
                    <lb/>Calling to minde the <unclear reason="illegible">fraiety</unclear> and <unclear reason="illegible">unsertaintie</unclear> of this present life and that
                    <lb/>all flesh must yield unto Death when it shall please god to call doe
                    <lb/>mark and ordaine this my last will and testmanet this <date>fifth day of
                    <lb/>march anno Domini 1677</date>. hereby revoking all former wills by me made either
                    <lb/>by word or writing and this to be my last will and noe other and first of
                    <lb/>all I bequeath my soule unto the mercifull hand of godalmighty
                    <lb/>who gave it my body unto the earth from here it came to be decently
                    <lb/>intered at direction of my Executors hereafter named hoping in and 
                    <lb/>through the merits and passion of my blessed savior Jesus Christ to 
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> and free pardon of all my sins to find a joyfull <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                    <lb/>and for what Temporal Estate and goods it hath pleased God of this
                    <lb/>bounty to bestowe upon me after my Just Debts which either in Laws or
                    <lb/>Convenience I owe are in due time satisfied I desiring to be dispersed of as
                    <lb/>as followeth.
                </p>
                <p>Item. I give and bequeath unto my Eldest sonne <persName type="eldestson" xml:id="RichardWade">Richard <surname>Wade</surname></persName> all that <measure commodity="land" quantity="450" unit="acre" xml:id="RichardWade">parcelor
                    <lb/>parcells of Land Called <name>Limme Lemis</name> <unclear reason="illegible">intangement</unclear> it be that Land whereon
                    <lb/>I now dwell Containing five hundred and fifty acres</measure> and also all that
                    <lb/><measure commodity="land" quantity="500" unit="acre" xml:id="RichardWade">parcell or parcells of Land called <name>Madeson and Madesons enlargement</name></measure>
                    <lb/>lying at <placeName>Goone bay</placeName> Containing <measure commodity="land" quantity="400" unit="acre">four hundred acres</measure> and also one <unclear reason="illegible">moeety</unclear>
                    <lb/>or half of that tract of Land Called <measure commodity="land" quantity="1060" unit="acre" xml:id="RichardWade"><name><unclear reason="illegible">Louest Thiehete</unclear></name> one thousand
                    <lb/>and sixtie acres</measure> being the Land which my brother <persName type="brother">Randolfe <surname>Hinson</surname></persName> &amp; bequeath
                    <lb/>og <persName type="beneficiary" xml:id="ThomasBrookes">Mr. Thomas <surname>Brookes</surname></persName> and also all that <measure commodity="land" xml:id="ThomasBrookes">tract of Land lying next the Indian
                    <lb/>line at the head of the <placeName>Pieatoway Creek</placeName></measure> all which said <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> I give and 
                    <lb/>bequeath unto my sone Richard Wade to him and his heirs forever
                    <lb/><catchwords>Item.</catchwords>
                </p>
                <pb/>
                <p>Item. I give and bequeath unto my sone <persName type="son" xml:id="RobertWade">Robert <surname>Wade</surname></persName> <measure commodity="land" quantity="600" unit="acre" xml:id="RobertWade">six hundred acres of a tract
                <lb/>of Land of twelve hundred acres called <name>Merkell overton</name></measure> lying at <unclear reason="illegible"><name>Pomonkey</name></unclear>
                    <lb/>and also all that of Land called Forest Green containing five
                    <lb/>hundred acres lying at <name>Pangia</name> and also all that parcel of Land called
                    <lb/><name>harboa</name> containing three hundred &amp; five acres lying upon the 
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible">branches</unclear> of <placeName><unclear reason="illegible">Piseataway Creek</unclear></placeName> and also two hundred acres Land called
                    <lb/><name>Friendship</name> being the land which I sealed above <placeName>Peicatoway</placeName> all which said
                    <lb/>parcells of Land I give and bequeath unto my said son Robert Wade to him
                    <lb/>and his heirs forever
                </p>
                <p>Item. I give and bequeath unto my Daughter <persName type="daughter" xml:id="TheodosiaWade">Theodosia <surname>Wade</surname></persName> the <measure type="land" xml:id="TheodosiaWade">one <unclear reason="illegible">moiety</unclear> or
                    <lb/>tract of Land which my brother <persName>Luke <surname>Gardiner</surname></persName> and I took up Together
                    <lb/>lying upon the <placeName>Eastern Branches of Pesiatoway</placeName></measure> and also all that tract or
                    <lb/>remainder of that parcell of Land called Markett Overton lying at 
                    <lb/><placeName>pomonkey</placeName> all which said land I give unto my said Daughter Theodosia
                    <lb/>Wade to her and her heirs forever.
                </p>
                <p>Item. I give and bequeath unto my sonn Richard Wade <measure commodity="horse" quantity="1">one mare and her increase</measure>
                    <lb/>that is now with her and all future Increase that she may bring and also
                    <lb/><measure commodity="crop" quantity="4000" unit="pounds" xml:id="RichardWade">four thousand pounds of Tobacco</measure> and <measure commodity="furniture" quantity="1">one feather bed half woarn</measure> and <measure commodity="other">pillows</measure>
                    <lb/><measure commodity="other" quantity="1">one plain rug</measure> and <measure commodity="other" quantity="1">one shaged rugg</measure> <measure commodity="other">curtains</measure> and <measure commodity="other">vallances</measure> and <measure commodity="linens" quantity="3">three pairs of
                    <lb/>sheets</measure> and the said maine to be dispersed as to the Dispositions of my
                    <lb/>Executors to my sones use and also <measure commodity="horse" quantity="1" xml:id="RichardWade">one negro bay named <name>black Jack</name></measure> all which
                    <lb/>said goods I give unto my sone Richard Wade and his heris forever.
                </p>
                <p>Item. I give and bequeath unto my sone Robert Wade the sum of <measure commodity="crop" quantity="3000" unit="pounds" xml:id="RobertWade">three thousand
                <lb/>pounds of tobacco</measure> and <persName type="enslaved">one negro boy</persName> I give unto my sone Robert to be bought 
                    <lb/>by my Executor for him and <measure commodity="horse" quantity="1" xml:id="RobertWade">one <unclear reason="illegible">dumm</unclear> mare</measure> and her increase and <measure commodity="furniture" quantity="1" xml:id="RobertWade">one
                    <lb/>feather bed</measure> and <measure commodity="linens" quantity="3" xml:id="RobertWade">three pairs of sheets</measure> with <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> blankets and <measure commodity="other" xml:id="RobertWade"><unclear reason="illegible">ruggs</unclear></measure>
                    <lb/>all which said goods I give and bequeath to my sone RobertWade to him and
                    <lb/>his heirs forever
                </p>
                <p>Item. I give and bequeath unto my Daughter Theodosia Wade one negro girl named <persName type="enslaved">
                    <lb/><catchwords>Judith</catchwords></persName>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>Judith and adoresaid maire and her increased and also <measure commodity="furniture" quantity="1" xml:id="TheodosiaWade">one feather bed</measure>
                    <lb/>and <measure commodity="linens" quantity="1" xml:id="TheodosiaWade">three pairs of sheets</measure> with <measure commodity="other" xml:id="TheodosiaWade">ruggs</measure> and <measure commodity="other" xml:id="TheodosiaWade">blankets</measure> and <measure commodity="clothes" xml:id="TheodosiaWade">all her mothers
                    <lb/>cloathes</measure> and <measure commodity="jewelry" xml:id="TheodosiaWade">rings</measure> and <measure commodity="houseware" quantity="1">one silver candell cup</measure> and <measure commodity="houseare" quantity="2" xml:id="TheodosiaWade">two spones</measure> which
                    <lb/>said goods I give and bequeath to my said Daughter Theodosia Wade
                    <lb/>to her and her heirs forever. 
                </p>
                <p>Item. I give unto my son Richard Wade forever <measure commodity="houseware" quantity="1" xml:id="RichardWade">one silver tankerd</measure> holds
                    <lb/>a quart and <measure commodity="houseware" quantity="1" xml:id="RichardWade">one silver spone</measure> to my son Robert Wade I give and
                    <lb/>bequeath <measure commodity="houseware" quantity="10" xml:id="RobertWade">ten silver spones</measure> and <measure commodity="houseware" quantity="1" xml:id="RobertWade">one small silver point cup</measure> and <measure commodity="houseware" quantity="2" xml:id="RobertWade">two
                    <lb/>small silver cups</measure> more to my said son Rob. forever. 
                </p>
                <p>Item. I give to <persName type="niece" xml:id="MaryHinson">Mary <surname>Hinson</surname></persName> the <measure commodity="horse" quantity="1" xml:id="MaryHinson">first mare fole</measure> that any of my mares 
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible">bungoth</unclear> this present year.
                </p>
                <p>Item. I give and bequeath unto my said three children the remainder or my
                    <lb/>Estate to be equally duvuded amongst them it is my will that if
                    <lb/>either or any of them him or her shall die before they come to age
                    <lb/>her or their part or portion of Land and other thing hereby bequeathed
                    <lb/>shall be equally divided amongs the survivers or survivor of in the 
                    <lb/>care it please God to take them all before they come to age their Estates
                    <lb/>bought of lands or ought <unclear reason="illegible">ese</unclear> shall be divided amongst the sones of
                    <lb/>my beloved brother in law <persName type="brother-in-law" xml:id="RandallHinson">Randall <surname>Hinson</surname></persName> and <persName type="executor" xml:id="WilliamHalton">William <surname>Haltons</surname></persName> sons
                </p>
                <p>Item. I make Constitute and appoint my wwell beloved brother Randall Hinson 
                    <lb/>and William Halton of <placeName>St. Marys County</placeName> gen. Executors and administrators
                    <lb/>of this my last will and testament earnestly desiring them to see this
                    <lb/>my will performed Intestimony hereof I have to this my last will
                    <lb/>and testament set my land and seal the day and year above written.
                </p>
                <p>Signed sealed and published
                    <lb/>In the presents of us
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">Abraham <unclear reason="illegible"><surname>Satploale</surname></unclear></persName>
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">John <surname>Greyot</surname></persName>
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">Richard <surname>Hodgson</surname></persName>
                    <lb/>Zachary Wade
                    <pb/>
                </p>
                <p>It is my free desire that my brother <persName type="executor">Randalfe <surname>Hinson</surname></persName> and brother being
                    <lb/>Executors
                   
                   
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>