<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="MD_CC_PRO_040_1670_Deane" xml:lang="en">Edward Deane Will</title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <author></author>
                <editor></editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Signed Sealed Delivered</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)">Edward Deane Will</head>
                <p>In the name of God Amen I<persName type="author">Edward <surname>Deane</surname></persName> being now very weak and <unclear reason="illegible">weake</unclear>
                    <lb/>but yet sound and perfect memory do in the presents of these ministers make this 
                    <lb/>my latest and last will and testament first bequeathing my soul to god 
                    <lb/>my maker and also my body to the Earth from where it came with decent 
                    <lb/>burial secondly to all and <unclear reason="illegible">wery</unclear> of my conditions his just <unclear reason="illegible">deces</unclear> and for all other 
                    <lb/>worldly goods as lands chattel hogs in of what sort werthat doth 
                    <lb/>properly belong into me I do hear in the presence of these <unclear reason="illegible">ministers</unclear> bequeath 
                    <lb/>them all and every of them unto <persName type="beneficiary">Elizabeth <surname>Lindsey</surname></persName> daughter of <persName>Mr. Hames <surname>Linsey</surname></persName> 
                    <lb/>of <placeName>Charles County in Maryland</placeName> appointing and ordaining her the said Elizabeth 
                    <lb/>after my decease my sole heir to enjoy and <unclear reason="illegible">prosper</unclear> all and every of such lands 
                    <lb/>chattle and good as in my lifetime did properly belong unto me for her and her 
                    <lb/>hares forever only I desiring the father of said Elizabeth and mother may 
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible">enjoy</unclear> <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> of al the said lands, chattels, and goods untill the said Elizabeth 
                    <lb/>shall be married or come of age as namely the plantation that <persName>Sarah 
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible"><surname>Cofer</surname></unclear></persName> <unclear reason="illegible">dwels</unclear> upon with all rights and benefits that doth or might 
                    <lb/>belong unto me and also <measure commodity="livestock" quantity="1">one heifer</measure> and <measure commodity="livestock" quantity="1">one younger sterne</measure> that is at <persName>John
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible"><surname>Wheelers</surname></unclear></persName> and one small <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> that with <unclear reason="illegible">name</unclear> and my <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> which is at 
                    <lb/><catchwords></catchwords>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/><persName>Bennet <unclear reason="illegible"><surname>Maguires</surname></unclear></persName> as also <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> and frying pan that is there therase and all other 
                    <lb/>Things that doath belong unto me Edward Deane I doe this <date>sixth day of April 
                    <lb/>in the year of our Lord Anno Domini One Thousand six hundred and twenty</date> 
                    <lb/>bequeath unto the said Elizabeth Lindsey after she shall come of age and her first 
                    <lb/>marriage to enjoy and <unclear reason="illegible">prosper</unclear> for she and her heirs forever <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> James &amp;
                    <lb/><persName>Mary <surname>Lindsey</surname></persName> the father and mother of the said Elizabeth to enjoy and <unclear reason="illegible">profits</unclear>
                    <lb/>all the contents of the above specified untill the said Elizabeth shall come of age 
                    <lb/>or be marryed and then to surrender the same unto the said Elizabeth and if 
                    <lb/>the said Elizabeth shall die before she shall come of age or be marryed then the 
                    <lb/>nearest of her kindred to enjoy the same sae committing my soule unto God I do 
                    <lb/>here in the presents of these <unclear reason="illegible">ministers</unclear> <unclear reason="illegible">confine</unclear> My last will and testament 
                    <lb/>and set to my hand and seal this day and year above written
                    <lb/>In the presents of us					
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">Ralph <surname>Coates</surname></persName>		
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">John <surname>Gosling</surname></persName>
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">Richard R <unclear reason="illegible"><surname>Wall</surname></unclear></persName> 
                    <lb/>Mark
                    <lb/>his mark
                    <lb/><signatures rend="align(right)">Edward X Deane</signatures>
                </p>
                <p>On the back of the forgoing was the forgoing was thus endorsed to <unclear reason="illegible">weit</unclear>
                    <lb/>To the honorable <persName type="endorsement">Mr. William <unclear reason="illegible">Fattoll</unclear> <surname>Baronett</surname></persName> Chief Judge of Testamentary causes 
                    <lb/>within the provinace of Maryland by virtue of a <unclear reason="illegible">commision</unclear> from his hon. <unclear reason="illegible">bearing</unclear>
                    <lb/>date y. <date>eight day of september in the <unclear reason="illegible">40th</unclear> year of the Dominion of <unclear reason="illegible">julius</unclear> <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                    <lb/>anno domini 1671</date> to me directed and me <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> to call before me the several
                    <lb/>witnesses to the last will and testament of Edward Deane <unclear reason="illegible">late</unclear> of <placeName>Charles County</placeName> deceased and by this oaths to <unclear reason="illegible">eause</unclear> the same to be approved these are humbly to <unclear reason="illegible">certifee</unclear> that on the 
                    <lb/><date>fourteenth day of september</date> in the year above came before me <persName>Ralph Bates</persName> 
                    <lb/>and <persName>Richard Wall</persName> two of the witnesses to the within written will and made oath 
                    <lb/>that they saw the written named Edward Deane sign seal and publish the within 
                    <lb/>writing as his last will and testament that he was in perfect <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> &amp;
                    <lb/>memory when he Executed the same.
                    <lb/>5 2/4 sides
                    <signatures>Benj.a Roger</signatures> <!-- Create a new tei element for this -->
                    </p>
                    
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>