<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="MD_CC_PRO_064_1678_Douglass" xml:lang="en">John Douglass Will</title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <editor>Emily Boyer</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>"Maryland, Register of Wills Records, 1629-1999." 
                    Images. FamilySearch. <ref target="http://FamilySearch.org">http://FamilySearch.org</ref>: 3 December 2024. 
                    Citing Prerogative Court. Hall of Records, Annapolis.</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p><ref><!-- link to primary source here --></ref></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)">John Douglass Will</head>
                <p><placeName>Charles County</placeName> In the name of God Amen.
                    <lb/>I <persName type="author">John Douglass</persName> of <placeName>Charles County in the province of Maryland</placeName>
                    <lb/>Gentleman being weake of body but of sound and perfect memory 
                    <lb/>praised be to God for the same doe make and ordaine this my
                    <lb/>last will and testament in manner &amp; so following that is to say
                    <lb/>first I bequeathmy soule to God from whome I had it hoping one
                    <lb/>day to make perfect through the pretious Death and passion of my 
                    <lb/>dear Saviour Jesus Christ and my body I commit to the earth from 
                    <lb/><catchwords>where</catchwords>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>where it came to be decently buried at the discression of my Executor hereafter
                    <lb/>named.
                </p>
                <p><unclear reason="illegible">Imp.</unclear> It is my will that all my Just Debts and funeral charges be paid and 
                   <lb/>satisfied Item I give unto my loving son <persName type="son" xml:id="JohnDouglassJr.">John <surname>Douglass</surname></persName> <measure commodity="land" quantity="550" unit="acre" xml:id="JohnDouglassJr.">five hundred
                       <lb/>and fifty acres of land</measure> being part of a parcell of land containing <measure commodity="land" quantity="1050" unit="acre" xml:id="JohnDouglassJr.">one
                   <lb/>thousand and fifty acreslaying at <placeName>Potucent</placeName> called <name>Cole Spring Manner</name></measure> 
                    <lb/>when he shall arrive all the age of one and twenty years wth all the 
                    <lb/>priviledges belonging to that Lord of manner and to his heirs lawfully
                    <lb/>to be gather of his body and for the want of such if use my will &amp; pleasure is
                    <lb/>that <measure commodity="land" quantity="225" unit="acre" xml:id="RobertDouglass">two hundred twenty and five acres</measure> the one <unclear reason="illegible">m</unclear> of the said five
                    <lb/>hundred and fifty acres with that privilege of the manner of the aforesaid <unclear reason="illegible">desired</unclear>
                    <lb/>unto my loving son Robert Douglass when he shall arrive at the full age
                    <lb/>of one and twenty years and the other <measure type="land" quantity="275" unit="acre" xml:id="JospehDouglass">two hundred and seventy five</measure> the <unclear reason="illegible">m</unclear> of
                    <lb/><persName type="son" xml:id="JosephDouglass">Joseph <surname>Douglass</surname></persName> when twenty one years old. 
                </p>
                <p>Item I give unto my loving son Robert Douglass <measure commodity="land" xml:id="RobertDouglass">all that parcel of Land called <name>Blute Wood</name></measure> lying in <placeName>Charles County</placeName> when he shall arrive at the full age of 
                    <lb/>one and twenty years.
                </p>
                <p>Item I give unto my loving sons <persName type="son" xml:id="CharlesDouglass">Charles <surname>Douglass</surname></persName> and Joseph Douglass <measure commodity="land" quantity="500" unit="acre">five
                <lb/>hundred acres of land being the remaining part of one thousand and fifty acres
                    <lb/>of Land</measure> lying at <unclear reason="illegible"><name>Petucen</name></unclear> called <name>Cole Spring Manner</name> when they shall arrive at the full age of twenty and onen years. 
                </p>
                <p>I give unto my dear and loving wife <persName type="spouse" xml:id="SarahDouglass">Sarah <surname>Douglass</surname></persName> all that <measure commodity="land" quantity="400" unit="acre" xml:id="SarahDouglass">four hundred
                <lb/>acres of land</measure> upon which I now live at <placeName>Pichiawacon</placeName> in <placeName>Charles County</placeName> to
                    <lb/>her and her heirs forever and on for what personal Estate God of his goodness
                    <lb/>hath bestowed upon me I give and bequeath unto my dear and loving wife
                    <lb/>Sarah Douglass whome I have apponted to be my sole Executor of this my last
                    <lb/>will and testament and hereby revoke and make void all wills by me 
                    <lb/>formally made on witness my hand and seal this <date>fourteenth day of December
                    <lb/>in the 3rd year</date> of the Dominion of <persName>Charles</persName> absolute Lord and propietary of
                    <lb/><catchwords>Maryland</catchwords>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>Maryland &amp;c. anno Domino <date>1678</date>.
                </p>
                <p>Signed Sealed and Published
                    <lb/>In the presence of us
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">Henry Bonner</persName> — <persName type="witness">Francis <surname>Pollen</surname></persName> — <persName type="witness">John <surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
                    <lb/>John Douglass
                </p>
                <p>On the back of the aforegoing will of <unclear reason="illegible">col.</unclear> John Douglass was thus en. <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                    <lb/>The within written wil of Col. John Douglass was proved before me in
                    <lb/>common form the <date>27th day of January 1678</date> by the oaths of Henry
                    <lb/>Bonner Francis Pollen and John Robinson witnesses to the same
                    <lb/>4 1/4 sides
                    <lb/>Benjamin Rozer
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>