<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="MD_CC_PRO_042_1675_Crefsey" xml:lang="en">Samuel Crefsey. Will</title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <author></author>
                <editor></editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Signed Sealed Delivered</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)">Samuel Crefsey. Will</head>
                <p>In the name of God Amen. I <persName type="author">Samuel Crefsey</persName> of <placeName>Charles County</placeName> being very
                    <lb/>sick and weake of body but praised be good for the same of sound and perfect
                    <lb/>emory do make ordaine &amp; constitute this my last will and testament in
                    <lb/>manner and form following first I bequeath my soul into the hands of almighty
                    <lb/>God that give it and my bpdy to the earth to be desently buried as shall please my
                    <lb/>Executor hereafter named trusting through the merrits of my Lord &amp;
Savior
<lb/><catchwords>Jesus</catchwords>
                    
                    <pb/>
                    
                    <lb/>Jesus Christ to obtain pardon and <unclear reason="illegible">profession</unclear> of all my offenses next I give and
                    <lb/>bequeath unto <persName type="beneficiary" xml:id="GeorgeRobertson">George <surname>Robertson</surname></persName> <measure commodity="horse" quantity="1" xml:id="GeorgeRobertson">one young bay horse branded with SC on
                    <lb/>rear buttock about thee years of age know by the name of <name>Robin</name></measure> and <measure commodity="livestock" quantity="1" xml:id="GeorgeRobertson">one
                    <lb/>yearling cow calf that came of <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> Called <name>Cole</name></measure> and one small <unclear reason="illegible">gunt</unclear> that
                    <lb/>the Indian hath out to hunt and I desire that he may be sent down to
                    <lb/><persName type="beneficiary" xml:id="RobertThomas">Robert <surname>Thomas</surname></persName> his wife son have hes head cured at the spring of the year
                    <lb/>next I desire all my Just Debts may be well and truly satisfied and
                    <lb/>for what land I hold in  the pronvince I doe give and bequeath unto my two
                    <lb/>Daughters <persName type="daughter" xml:id="MaryCrefsey">Mary</persName> and <persName type="daughter" xml:id="SusannaCrefsey">Susanna</persName> when they shall come to years of Age
                    <lb/>Likewise the remainder of my Estate I give and bequeath every part &amp; parcel thereof
                    <lb/>to my said two Daughters to be equally divided beween them when thet come 
                    <lb/>to years of <unclear reason="illegible">disifson</unclear>.
                </p>
                <p>And I do hereny nominate and appoint <persName type="executor" xml:id="RichardEdelin">Richard <surname>Edelin</surname></persName> my loving friend
                    <lb/>to see this my last will and testament performed to whome I doe bequeath
                    <lb/><measure commodity="jewelry" quantity="1" xml:id="RichardEdelin">one seale ring</measure> sent me out of <placeName>England</placeName> but as <unclear reason="illegible">yet</unclear> on board <persName>Capt. Paine</persName>
                    <lb/>hereby revoking all former or other wills by me made  In witness whereof
                    <lb/>I have hereunto set my hand and seal this <date>21st of January 1676</date>.
                </p>
                <p>Signed Sealed and Delivered
                    <lb/>In presence of us
                    <lb/><persName type="witness">Ann</persName> <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>; <persName type="witness">Henry <unclear reason="illegible">Trent</unclear></persName>
                    <lb/>Sa. Crifsey
                </p>
                <p>On the back of the aforegoing was the following probits (to wit)
                    <lb/><date>4th February 1675</date>. Henry Trent made oath that he was preset at the signing
                    <lb/>Sealing and Delivering of the within Last Will and Testament by the within
                    <lb/><unclear reason="illegible">Testator</unclear> and that at the signing sealed and Delivering thereof he was
                    <lb/>around dispersing mine with an intent to make it as his last will and 
                    <lb/>testament before me signed by order of the Judge Testamentary.
                    <lb/><persName type="clerk">Michael Readford</persName> Clerk
                </p>
                <p><unclear reason="illegible">Ann</unclear> <unclear reason="illegible">Steppo</unclear> made oath that she was present at the signing sealing and
                    <lb/>Delivery of the within last will and testament by the within testator
                    <lb/>and that at the signing sealing and Delivery thereof he was of sound <unclear reason="illegible">desiring</unclear>
                    <lb/><catchwords>mind</catchwords>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>minf with a intent to make it as hes last will and testament before me
                    <lb/><date>Feb. the 6th 1675/6</date>
                    <lb/>5 1/2 sides
                    <lb/>Lean <unclear reason="illegible">Jourdan</unclear>
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>