<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="MD_CC_PRO_057_1676_Corker" xml:lang="en">Thomas Corker. Will.</title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <author></author>
                <editor>Emily Boyer</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Signed Sealed Delivered</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)">Thomas Corker. Will.</head>
                <p>In the name of God Amen. <date>November 17 day 1676</date>.
                    <lb/>I <persName type="author">Thomas <surname>Corker</surname></persName> of <placeName>Charles County in the province of Maryland</placeName>
                    <lb/>being
                    <lb/>sick in body But of good and perfect memory thanks be to Almighty
                    <lb/>god and calling to remembrance the uncertain Estate of this 
                    <lb/>transitory life and that al flesh mud yeild unto Death when
                    <lb/>it shall please god to call doe make Constitute ordaine and declare
                    <lb/>this my last will and testament in manner and form following
                    <lb/>reworking and <unclear reason="illegible">admulling</unclear> by these presents all and very testmanent and 
                    <lb/>testaments will and wills heretofore by me made and declared
                    <lb/>either by word or written and this is to be taken only for my last
                    <lb/>will and testament and none other and first being <unclear reason="illegible">pernitent</unclear> and
                    <lb/>sorry from the bottom of my heart for my sinns past most humbly
                    <lb/>desiring <unclear reason="illegible">foregivenets</unclear> of all my sins and that my soule
                    <lb/>with my body at the general day of resurrection shall rise again
                    <lb/>with joy and through the merits of Christs Death and passion
                    <lb/>profets and inherit the kingdom of heaven prepared for his eleet &amp;
                    <lb/>chosen and my body to be buried in such place wheare it shal please my 
                    <lb/>Executor hereafter named to appoint and now for the selling of my
                    <lb/>temporal Estate and such goods chattles and debts as it hath pleased God
                    <lb/>far above my deserts to bestow whom my I doe order give and disphose
                    <lb/>the same in manner and form following that is to say first I will that 
                    <lb/>person or persons what <unclear reason="illegible">saever</unclear> shall be well and truly contented and
                    <lb/>paid or ordained to be paud within convenient time after my
                    <lb/>decease <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> Executor hereafter named.
                </p>
                <p><catchwords>Item.</catchwords>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>Item. I give and bequeath all my hole Estate and personal unto my dear and 
                    <lb/>Loving wife <persName type="spouse" xml:id="ElizabethCorker">Elizabeth <surname>Corker</surname></persName> doe hereby appoint and ordaine her my
                    <lb/>heir and sole Executor exception some shall <unclear reason="illegible">Legaires</unclear> hear after mentioned
                </p>
                <p>Item. I give and bequeath unto <persName type="beneficiary" xml:id="PhillopRogg">Phillop <surname>Rogg</surname></persName> <measure commodity="horse" quantity="1">one brown mare with <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                    <lb/>in her forehead called by the name of <name>Brammion</name></measure> foaled which <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> by
                    <lb/>her side of the said mare hase one if not to have the next that the
                    <lb/>said mare shall bring
                </p>
                <p>Item. I give and bequeath unto <persName type="beneficiary" xml:id="BenjaminRozer">Mr. Benjamin <surname>Rozer</surname></persName> <measure></measure>
                    
                </p>
                
                <p>Utem. I give and bequeath unto <persName type="beneficiary" xml:id="WilliamChandler">Willam <surname>Chandler</surname></persName>
                    
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>