<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="xx" xml:lang="en"><!-- Title ex. John Smith. Will --></title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <author></author>
                <editor></editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Signed Sealed Delivered</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)">Giles Cole. Will.</head>
                <p>In the name of God Amen. I <persName type="author">Giles Cole</persName> of <placeName>Charles County</placeName> in the
                    <lb/>provence of maryland planter being disparaleley wounded by the Susquehanna
                    <lb/>Indians but of sound and perfect memory praised bee unto almighty God and 
                    <lb/><catchwords>Knowing</catchwords>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>knowing that all flesh must yeild unto Death when it shall please God
                    <lb/>Almighty to call do make this my last will and testament in manner and form
                    <lb/>following that is to say first and principally I commit my soul into the hands of
                    <lb/>Almighty God my maker who gave it <unclear reason="illegible">hoping</unclear> through the <unclear reason="illegible">meritorious</unclear>
                    <lb/>Death and passion of our blessed Savior Jesus Christ to receive free pardon
                    <lb/>for all my sins past and my body to the earth to be desently buried from where
                    <lb/>it Came and as for what wordly Estate God of his infinite goodness hath been
                    <lb/>pleased to make me <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> and of in this testimony I give and bequeath in
                    <lb/>manner and form following. 
                </p>
                <p>First I give and bequeath unto <persName type="beneficiary">John <surname>Hawkins</surname> Jun.</persName> one young stone horse of two
                    <lb/>years and hald old to be delivered unto him after my decrease
                </p>
                <p>Secondly. I give and bequeath unto <persName type="beneficiary">Henry <surname>Hawkins</surname></persName> brother of the above said John <measure commodity="horse" quantity="1">one gray mare
                    <lb/>marked with HH</measure> together with all her future increase to him and his heirs forever
                    <lb/>to be delivered unto him immedietly after my decease.
                </p>
                <p>Thirdly I give 
                    
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>