<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="file:/Users/emilyboyer/Desktop/ssdmain/repo/ssd.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title xml:id="MD_CC_PRO_053_1673_Goodrick" xml:lang="en">George Goodrick Will</title>
                <!-- xml: id ex. MD_CC_PRO_034_1665_Lumbrozo -->
                <author></author>
                <editor>Emily Boyer</editor>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>Signed Sealed and Delivered</publisher>
                
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>This is the source</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head rend="align(center)">George Goodrick Will</head>
                <p>In the name of God Amen. The <date>26th of July anno Dominion
                <lb/>thousand six hundred seventie three</date> I <persName type="author">George <surname>Goodrick</surname></persName> of <placeName>Charles County
                <lb/>in the prov. of Maryland</placeName> <unclear reason="illegible">Gen.</unclear> being sick and weake of bodie but of
                    <lb/>sound and perfect memory praise be given to God and knowing the 
                    <lb/><catchwords>uncertaintie</catchwords>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>uncertantie of this life and being Desirous of setting things in order doe
                    <lb/>make this my last will and testament in manner and form following that
                    <lb/>is to say first and principally I commend my solute to God hoping that
                    <lb/>by the merits of my saviour Jesus Christ I shall <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>
                    <lb/>my sins and my body to the earth from where it come to be buried in
                    <lb/>such decent and Christian manner as my Executor shal think fit ans as
                    <lb/>for my wordly Estate which God through his many hath let me my will
                    <lb/>and meaning is the same shall be implayed and <unclear reason="illegible">beloved</unclear> as hereafter
                    <lb/>by this my last will is <unclear reason="illegible">expressed</unclear> and first I will and require that all my
                    <lb/>just debts be satisfied discharged and paid and I doe hereby <unclear reason="illegible">unaumee</unclear>
                <lb/><unclear reason="illegible">frustraite</unclear> and make said all wills by me foremly made and declare this
                    <lb/>to be my last will and testament.
                </p>
                <p>Itm. f. I give and bequeath unto my two sonnes <persName type="son" xml:id="RobertGoodrick">Robert</persName> and <persName type="son" xml:id="FrancisGoodrick">Francis <surname>Goodrick</surname></persName> six
                <lb/>hunedred acres which I have by patent  that is to say <measure commodity="land" quantity="300" unit="acre" xml:id="RobertGoodrick">thee hundred</measure> to Robert
                    <lb/>Goodrick and <measure commodity="land" quantity="300" unit="acre">three hundred</measure> to Francis Goodrick next adjoining to the 
                    <lb/>plantation where they now live <unclear reason="illegible">leyaline</unclear> drawn equalie between them
                    <lb/>and to them and their heirs forever which division may be made by the
                    <lb/>bounds expressed in my said patent.
                </p> 
                <p>2 I doe give and to my Daughter <persName type="daughter" xml:id="Stapleford">Stapleford</persName> <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> two years old
                    <lb/>with <unclear reason="illegible">adesine</unclear> that my dear child unintelegable may have the
                    <lb/>3 increase and <unclear reason="illegible"></unclear> other wares to be dispersed of I give and bequeath
                    <lb/>to my daughter <persName type="daughter" xml:id="Guntryt"><unclear reason="illegible">Guntryt</unclear></persName> <measure commodity="livestock" quantity="1">on heifer</measure> more of the same age with the same 
                    <lb/>intent and desire that my grandchild <persName type="grandchild" xml:id="ConstantGuntryt">Constant <surname>Guntryt</surname></persName> my have the
                    <lb/>increase also
                    <lb/>4 I give and bequeath unto my sonne<persName type="son" xml:id="FrancisGoodrick">Francis <surname>Goodrick</surname></persName> <measure commodity="livestock" quantity="1" xml:id="FrancisGoodrick">one cow</measure> with a cow 
                        <lb/>calf and the calf to be for my grand child <persName type="granddaughter" xml:id="ElizabethGoodrick">Elizabeth <surname>Goodrick</surname></persName> and the
                    <lb/>increase forever.
                </p>
                <p>5 also I give and bequeath unto my sonn Francis Goodrick <measure commodity="furniture" quantity="1">an old feather 
                <lb/>bed</measure> with the absolute belonging to it which I brought out of England 
                    <lb/>6 and my <measure commodity="houseware">large iron pot</measure> and my least <measure commodity="houseware" quantity="1" xml:id="FrancisGoodrick"><unclear reason="illegible">Brass</unclear> pot</measure> <measure commodity="houseware" xml:id="FrancisGoodrick">two pueter dishes</measure>
                    <lb/><catchwords>and</catchwords>
                    <pb/>
                    <lb/>and <measure commodity="textile" quantity="1" xml:id="FrancisGoodrick">a bed rug</measure> for a bed. All the rest of my godds and chattles whatsoever
                    <lb/>I give and bequeath unto my sonne Robert Goodrick and to his heirg for
                    <lb/>ever and I doe hereby constitute and appoint my two sonnes
                    <lb/>Robert and Francis Goodrick the Executor of this my Estate and I doe
                    <lb/>desire <persName type="overseer" xml:id="ThomasMatthews">Mr. Thomas <surname>Matthews</surname></persName> and <persName type="overseer" xml:id="IgnatiusCausin">Mr. Ignatius <surname><unclear reason="illegible"></unclear>Causin</surname></persName> to bee the overseers
                    <lb/>of this my last will and testament ano in witness whereof I have set my
                    <lb/>hand and seal the day and year first above written
                </p>
                <p>sign seal in
                    <lb/>The presence of us
                    <lb/>Thomas Matthews
                    <lb/>Ignatius Causin
                    <lb/>George Goodrick
                </p>
                <p>On the back  of the aforegoing will was endorsed the follow probates to will
                    <lb/><placeName>Maryland</placeName> Js <date>September 9th 1676</date> By viture of a commission from the
                    <lb/>Judge un testmentary causes within this province dated the <date>31st of
                    <lb/>march 1676</date>. I called before me Ignatius Causin one of the witnesses to the
                    <lb/>within written will who proved the same by his oath before me
                    <lb/>5 1/2 sides
                    <lb/><persName>Benjamin Rozer</persName>
                </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>